NICOLE DREON

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | WEB DESIGNER

CONNECT



248-770-1925



Detroit, MI



dreon.nicole@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/nicoledreon/



github.com/NicoleDreon

MY BACKGROUND

You may be asking yourself how a psychology graduate turned yoga instructor found her way into the world of computer science? I've always had a very inquisitive mind and find joy in solving problems, it was only a matter of time before I found coding. I've just completed a 400 hour frontend bootcamp through Grand Circus in 10 weeks where I learned the technical skills required to create user friendly applications. My background in psychology and as a yoga professional give me a unique understanding of users and how to turn a client's vision into reality with the flexibility to make adjustments on the spot. This drives me to invent highly intuitive and functional applications that create a memorable user experience.

HOBBIES

- Hiking/Camping
- Snowboarding

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML5/CSS
- JavaScript
- Angular
- Node.JS
- JSON

- HTTP
- Git/GitHub
- TypeScript
- SQL
- Web APIs
- Pair Programming
- Responsive Design
- Wireframe
- Debug
- Figma

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Grand Circus

Front End Bootcamp | Oct 2020 - Dec 2020

Projects

POS Application: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Recipe Finder: Angular, Typescript, HTML, CSS

Young Chef - teaching kids to cook: Angular, TypeScript, SQL, API, HTML, CSS

Adrian College

Bachelor of Science in Psychology

Minor: Spanish Study Abroad: Mexico

WORK EXPERIENCE

Chalfonte Foundation

Program Director | July 2019 - July 2020

- Designed and executed the largest summer camp to date coordinating staff, organizing activities, setting timetables, and logistics.
- Planned, organized, and prepared for events local outings, day trips, and fundraising
- Managed and diffused conflict when it arose amongst youth from talking one on one to facilitating groups to resolve conflict including taking responsibility for actions and developing a plan for the future when appropriate.
- Managed staff trained 3 prior campers to be camp counselors which led to growth in their overall confidence.

Independent Contractor - In person and online

Yoga and Meditation Instructor | January 2018 - present

- Private sessions identify students goals and desired outcome, create bespoke classes, adjust as needed ensuring student is moving in the direction of their goals.
- Public classes (up to 50 students) plan and prepare flow, create a welcoming environment, read the room and adjust previously planned class for students ability and need (i.e. simplifying, picking up the pace, explaining in different terms, etc.).

Europe, Southeast Asia, Australia

Explorer | December 2016 - August 2017

Other Work Experience

UpDog Yoga - Front Desk and Yoga Instructor | August 2017 - July 2019 Whole Foods - Customer Service | Oct 2017 - July 2018 Carl's Pharmacy - Clerk to Pharmacy Technician | January 2009 - November 2016